holden.com.au 2013-04-24

# Privacy Policy

Holden complies with the National Privacy Principles. 

Holden respects the rights of individuals to determine to whom they give their personal information and how this information is used. Holden collects and uses your information in order to provide better customer service by striving to meet your needs and expectations about our cars and other products. We will not sell your information to any other organisation. 

We will be fair and open about the way we collect information about you and what we intend to do with the information. We share information about you with our affiliated companies and related companies, like General Motors, Daewoo and contracted service providers, as well as dealers to assist them to improve the quality and standard of service they provide to you. We also provide information to industry bodies and others for the purposes of audits of our records. Our Dealers, affiliated companies and related companies share information with us about you so that we can learn more about your expectations of us and how we can meet them. Where practicable, we will collect personal information directly from you. If we receive information about you from someone else or provide information to someone else about you, like our Dealers or contractors providing services to us, wherever possible we will make sure they comply with the Privacy Act. 

We will be open with you about the kinds of personal information we hold and what we do with it. We will strive to ensure that information about you is accurate when we collect or use it. Wherever possible and appropriate we will let you see the information we hold about you and correct it if it is wrong. If we do not grant you access to your personal information we will tell you why. 

We will keep your information secure. Only properly authorised people are permitted to see or use it. We will take steps to protect your privacy if we send personal information about you outside Australia. 

When we no longer use your information we will take care to properly de-identify it or destroy it. 

If you are unhappy with the way we have collected, used or shared your information we will investigate and respond to your complaint. Please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT HOLDEN'S USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION GENERALLY

_(a)Holden's use and disclosure of personal information_

**Warranty**

As part of the purchase of your new Holden vehicle, you usually obtain Holden's new vehicle warranty. Holden collects personal information from your Holden dealer when you purchase your new vehicle so that Holden can ensure that any warranty claim is properly administered. 

If you withdraw your consent to Holden collecting your personal information from your dealer for this purpose, this will affect Holden's ability to process your warranty claims. 

**Product Recalls**

Holden collects personal information from your Holden Dealer when you purchase your new vehicle so that Holden can ensure that you are contacted as soon as possible in the event of a safety related product recall. 

**Holden Assist/Roadside Assistance/Extended Warranty**

Holden engages contractors to provide Holden Assist, Holden Roadside Assistance and Holden's Extended Vehicle Warranty. Holden's agreements with these contractors require them to deal with your personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act. Holden Assist, Holden Roadside Assistance and Holden Extended Vehicle Warranty brochures provide you with more information about these services. 

If you withdraw your consent to Holden disclosing your personal information to these contractors, this will affect Holden's ability to deliver these services to you. 

**GM Holden MasterCard**

The GM Holden MasterCard is offered and administered by Westpac Banking Corporation. Westpac collects personal information from applicants and card holders and participating organisations, and discloses some of this information to Holden for the purposes of ensuring that card holders are able to claim their GM Holden MasterCard rebate when purchasing an eligible Holden vehicle. Please also see _"(c) How is my personal information used?"_ below for further details. 

If you withdraw your consent to Holden obtaining this information from Westpac, you will not be able to claim your GM Holden MasterCard rebate because Holden will be unable to collect or verify your entitlement to a rebate. 

**Customer and Product Surveys**

From time to time Holden surveys its customers regarding their satisfaction with Holden's products and services and the products and services provided by its Dealers and contracted services providers, such as Roadside Assistance. 

If you do not wish to participate in any survey received from Holden, please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). Holden will note your request and respect your wish not to receive any future surveys. 

If you choose not to participate in surveys conducted by Holden, Holden is less able to improve its products and services and the products and services provided by its Dealers and contracted service providers. 

**Direct Marketing**

From time to time Holden sends marketing materials to its customers and other people who have provided Holden with personal information about products and services offered by Holden, its Dealers and its affiliates. 

If you do not wish to receive marketing materials from Holden or its affiliates, please complete the opt-out provision on the marketing information sent to you and return it to Holden (or contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com)). Holden will note your request and respect your wish not to receive any marketing materials. 

If you choose not to receive any marketing materials from Holden, you may miss out on special product and service offerings and opportunities. 

**Event Data Recorders**

Holden vehicles, like other modern motor vehicles, have a number of sophisticated computer systems that monitor and control several aspects of the vehicle's performance. Holden vehicles use on-board vehicle computers to monitor emission control components to optimize fuel economy, to monitor conditions for air bag deployment and, if so equipped, to provide anti-lock braking and to help the driver control the vehicle in difficult driving situations. Some information may be stored during regular operations to facilitate repair of detected malfunctions; other information is stored only in certain collision events by computer systems, such as those commonly called event data recorders (EDR). The information from EDR's, if available, is used to improve customer and driver safety, better understand what happens to our vehicles in the event of a collision and shall be provided to the police on request. 

**Recruitment**

If you send Holden an application for a job or resume, Holden will use this information to assess your application and may disclose this information to its related companies (both in Australia and overseas) and contracted service providers for purposes such as aptitude, psychological and medical testing and human resources management activities. As part of the application process you will be asked for your specific consent for Holden to obtain information about your pre-employment medical examination (including drug and alcohol testing) and psychological and aptitude testing and the use and disclosure of the results of those tests.   
A refusal to provide any of this information, or to consent to its disclosure to Holden or to allow Holden to provide this information to the parties described above, may affect the success of your application. 

Holden may also ask you whether you agree to your personal information being provided to Holden's related companies and affiliates overseas for other positions relevant to your qualifications and experience that may arise. For example, HOLDEN's operations in: 

**\- Australia and New Zealand  
\- Asia Pacific   
\- Latin America and Middle East   
\- North America   
\- Europe   
**   
If you wish to obtain access to the personal information which Holden holds about you, please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

_(b) What Information Holden Collects_

The main ways in which Holden collects personal information from you is from information you provide to our Dealers (who then provide that information to us), market surveys, product focus groups, the Websites operated by Holden, Westpac (if you have a GM Holden MasterCard Westpac provides Holden with information), Holden's customer assistance service (via mail, email, telephone enquiries and EOR's). 

The personal information collected by Holden is likely to include a range of information including your name, address, telephone number, driver's license, date of birth, your vehicle's vehicle identification number, colour, features, make and model, place registered, registration date, registration number, engine size and transmission type, driver information (brake pedal position, accelerator position, speed, seat belt usage and airbag deployment), change of address and telephone information, amount of your GM Holden MasterCard rebate and the expiry date of your rebate points, any other information you may voluntarily provide to us. 

_(c) Complaints Handling & Contact Details_

If you have a complaint regarding Holden's management of your personal information or wish to correct any errors in the personal information Holden holds about you, please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

Holden will provide written acknowledgement of your complaint within 7 days of receipt. We will investigate and advise you of the steps we have taken to resolve your complaint. 

Holden will make the corrections requested to your personal information it holds within 30 days of receipt of your request. If Holden does not agree to your request for correction, it will notify you of the reasons it does not agree and will note your request on the records it holds about you. 

Holden relies on the accuracy of personal information as provided to it directly or indirectly. We encourage you to contact us if the personal information we hold about you is incorrect by contacting Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

_(d) Access_

If you wish to obtain access to your personal information held by Holden, please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

Holden will provide written acknowledgement of receiving your request for access within 7 days of receipt. Unless it does not agree to your request for access of personal information, in most cases Holden will provide you with access within 30 days of receipt of your request. If you request corrections to your personal information, if Holden does not agree to your request for correction, it will notify you of the reasons it does not agree and will note your request on the records it holds about you. If Holden agrees with your request these changes will be made as soon as practicable. 

_(e) Transfers Inside and Outside Australia_

Holden will ensure that contractors, affiliated companies and related companies that need to see personal information are compliant with the Privacy Act or a legislative regime which is at least as rigorous as the Privacy Act. All agreements with these third parties will impose this obligation. You can contact these third parties directly to request access to the personal information they hold about you. 

_(f) Information Storage & Security_

Holden stores personal information in transmission logs and archive systems for a period Holden considers reasonable depending on the primary purpose for which that information was collected. Only personnel who have a need to access personal information to perform their job will have access to that information. The physical and electronic security systems at Holden comply with the recommendations of the Federal Privacy Commissioner. 

_(g) Destruction and de-identification_

Personal information will be de-identified or destroyed when it is no longer required. The de-identification and destruction process will be in accordance with the recommendations of the Federal Privacy Commissioner and will ensure that the personal information cannot be re-identified at a later date. 

_(h) Training of staff_

Holden will ensure that its employees receive training (and refresher training) about the management of personal information relevant to their respective roles and responsibilities. Only properly authorised people are permitted to see or use personal information held by Holden. 

FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT HOLDEN'S PRIVACY POLICY AND USE OF ITS WEBSITES 

1\. PRIVACY AND USE OF WEBSITE   
Holden has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for Holden's websites, and answers the following questions: 

(a) What kind of information does Holden collect?   
(b) Do I have to provide personal information?   
(c) How is my personal information used?   
(d) What if I'm under 18 years of age?   
(e) How can I correct and update my personal information, member preferences, or unsubscribe/remove data from Holden's database?   
(f) Who can I ask if I have any additional questions? 

_(a) What kind of information does Holden collect?_   
When you look at any of Holden's Websites, our internet service provider logs the following information for statistical purposes: 

\- your server address   
\- your top level domain name (eg. .com, .org, .net, .au, etc.)   
\- the date and time of your visit   
\- the type of browser you are using   
\- the previous site you have visited   
\- the pages you accessed and the documents you downloaded 

PLEASE NOTE: Holden does not provide facilities for the safe transmission of information across the Internet. You should be aware that there are inherent risks in transmitting information across the Internet. 

_(b) Do I have to provide personal information?_   
No. You can visit Holden's Websites as a guest while remaining anonymous by not providing any personal information to us. Although, without this information, you will not be able to fully access all of the features and functionality of the site. However, our servers automatically collect some limited information about your visit that is not personally identifiable to you (see question (a)). 

Holden sometimes uses "cookies" to track and record your preferences and activity on our Website. Cookies are small bits of data that are sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive. Your cookie may be set at various times during your interaction with our Website. It is updated from time to time as you access the many different portions of our Website. Each time you access our site, our server may deliver certain customised information to you based on the data stored in your cookie. Wherever Holden collects personal information, we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page. 

_(c) How is my personal information used?_   
Holden's goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customised experience on our Website. Our site uses various forms for gathering information when applicable. Registration, survey and competition forms all, to some extent, require input of personal information. These forms require users to give us contact information (like name and email address), demographic information (like post code, age, or income level), and other applicable information. This information is used to send out prizes to contest winners, to contact the visitor when necessary, to send out information about Holden or its products or Websites that may be of interest to you, and to respond to your queries. 

We may also use the information to estimate the size of our audience and measure certain traffic patterns, to track the progress and number of entries in our promotions and contests, to track visits to linked sites, to notify our visitors about updates to our Website, and to contact you for marketing purposes and provide you with information regarding special events sponsored by Holden. 

If you ever receive a type of communication that you would not like to receive, you will have the option to unsubscribe from such communication (usually at the bottom of the page).   
Holden does not sell, rent, or trade your personal information with others. 

_(d) What if I'm under 18?_   
If you are under 18 years of age, you need to let your parent or guardian know about Holden's Privacy Policy and get their permission before giving us any of your personal information. You must get your parent or guardian's permission before using any message board or chat feature on Holden's Websites. 

DO NOT post your real name on this or any Website, and never tell anyone online anything private about yourself. 

If you win a contest that has a prize, your parent or guardian will have to mail us a signed note to the address listed in the rules for the contest that says it was OK for you to enter, and tells us they will accept the prize for you. 

Some areas of Holden's Website may have special rules for children under the age of 18. When you are in those areas, you must follow those rules. 

FOR PARENTS: 

Parents or guardians are encouraged to spend time online with their children to become familiar with the types of content available on Holden's Websites (and the Internet in general). Parents should regularly oversee their children's usage of email and other online communications and transactional features. Control tools are available for online services and there are software manufacturers that can help provide a safe online environment for children. 

If your child has provided us with personally identifiable information you should contact us immediately by sending an email to [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com) advising us of the Holden Website your child has visited and the information you wish to have deleted. We will make all reasonable efforts to delete your child's information from our records. 

_(e) How can I correct and update my personal information, member preferences, or unsubscribe/remove data from Holden's database?_   
In some cases, our Websites provide users the opportunity to change and modify information previously provided as well as opting-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about the visitor. If you wish to correct any errors in the personal information Holden holds about you, please contact Holden's Customer Assistance on 1800 033 349 or email us at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com). 

_(f) Further questions?_   
If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of any of Holden's Websites, or your dealings with any of Holden's Websites, you can contact us on: [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com) or 1800 033 349. 

2\. CONDITIONS OF USE OF WEBSITES 

_(a) Intellectual property rights_   
No part of Holden's Websites may be reproduced without express written permission from Holden. © GM Holden Ltd 2002-Thu Apr 25 06:45:19 EST 2013. All rights reserved. Holden shall enforce its rights concerning its Websites in the event of any interference, infringement or contravention of Holden's rights, title or interests in any aspect of this Website. This Website is protected under the copyright laws of Australia and other countries. Unless otherwise specified, no person has permission to download, display, post, record, "mirror", duplicate, copy, retransmit, redistribute, commercially exploit, reproduce or republish any part or aspect of this Website in any form, or any information found at this Website, by any means whatsoever, whether by electronic, mechanical, recording, photocopying, photographic means or otherwise. 

The symbols ® and ™ designate Australian registered trade-marks and unregistered trade-marks respectively. Holden and its parent General Motors Company have additional trade-marks and service marks, registered and unregistered, in other countries. Nothing on this Website shall be construed as conferring any license under any of Holden's or GMC's or any other person's intellectual property rights, whether expressly, by interference, by implication, or otherwise. Materials may not be copied or re-broadcast or redistributed or disseminated in any way without prior written permission of the copyright owner of that material. 

_(b) Consent_   
By using our Websites, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by Holden as outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

_(c) Statutory rights_   
You may have rights under the Australian Consumer Law or similar legislation which cannot be excluded or limited by Holden. These conditions of use do not, and do not intend to, exclude or limit those statutory rights in any way. 

_(d) Limitation of liability_   
Subject to (c) above and to the extent permitted by law, Holden shall not be liable for any damages, harm, liability, loss, cost, expense, or injury suffered in any connection with this Website whatsoever, including as a result of using, accessing, copying, or downloading any part of this Website's content. Subject to (c) above, in no event shall Holden be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damage or for any loss of business, revenue, profits, use, data or other economic advantage, however it arises, whether for breach of contract, or in tort, negligence, equity, or otherwise even if Holden has been previously advised of the possibility of such damage. You agree to hold Holden absolutely harmless from, and you covenant not to take any action against Holden for, any claims based on using this Website. 

_(e) Terms and Conditions of Use_   
By using this site, you agree to be bound by these Terms and Conditions of Use in relation to your use or the performance of this Website, and the information, services and material contained in it or provided by it. If you do not accept these Terms and Conditions of Use, please exit this Website.   
You may contact Holden at [customerassistance.holden@gm.com](mailto:customerassistance.holden@gm.com) or 1800 033 349 if you have any queries about these Terms and Conditions of Use or to provide us with any information or discuss any of the services we offer. 

1\. Introduction   
(a) You should read these Terms and Conditions of Use carefully.   
(b) In these Terms and Conditions of Use:   
(i) We", "Our" or "Us" means Holden Ltd ACN 006 893 232; and   
(ii) "You" or "Your" means the person who accepts these Terms and Conditions of Use.   
(c) Acceptance by You of these Terms and Conditions of Use binds You and all of Your employees, officers and agents to comply with these Terms and Conditions of Use. 

2\. Your privacy and security   
We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will comply with our legal and contractual obligations to You with respect to preserving the confidentiality of information relating to Your use of this Website and, accordingly, will not release information relating to Your use of this Website to a third party without Your consent. By using this Website You agree that information collected relating to Your use of this Website including your email address may be used by Us to analyse use of the Website and to tailor marketing by Us, Our subsidiaries, Our associated companies and/or companies managed by Us of products and services to You. This site uses a security device known as a Secure Socket Layer (SSL). This conforms to international standards and ensures that information passed to and from our Website cannot be viewed in transit. We strongly recommend You use this feature. You can tell if You are using the SSL by the appearance of a small padlock in the bottom status bar or on Your browser. The address in Your browser should start with https:// and not the usual http://. 

3\. Your information   
(a) All information provided by You in making use of this Website or any of the information, services or material provided by this Website must be accurate and complete. You must immediately update this information if it changes.   
(b) If any of Your information is incomplete or inaccurate, We may deny You access to this Website.   
(c) You must not disclose Your password to any third party or use Your password for any unauthorised purpose. 

4\. Binding terms and conditions   
(a) The only terms which are binding upon Us are:   
(i) those set out in these Terms and Conditions of Use; and   
(ii) those which are imposed by law and which may not be lawfully excluded.   
(b) We may vary these Terms and Conditions of Use at any time and without notice by posting the varied Terms and Conditions of Use on this Website. Your continued use of this Website after the Terms and Conditions of Use have been varied, constitutes Your acknowledgment that You accept the changes to the Terms and Conditions of Use and that You agree to be bound by the varied Terms and Conditions of Use. 

5\. Exclusions and limitations   
(a) You may have rights under the Australian Consumer Law or similar legislation which cannot be excluded or limited by Us. These conditions of use, including this clause 5, do not, and do not intend to, exclude or limit those statutory rights in any way.   
(b) All statutory or implied terms, conditions or warranties concerning the quality or condition of this Website or any information, service, material, advice or recommendation supplied by Us to You through this Website are excluded to the fullest extent permitted by law.   
(c) If We breach any consumer guarantee, term, condition or warranty which is implied or imposed by law and which cannot lawfully be excluded, to the extent that We are entitled to do so, We limit Our liability is limited to, at Our election:   
(i) the resupply of the relevant advice, service, recommendation or information; or   
(ii) the payment to You of the cost of having the relevant advice, service, recommendation or information supplied again.   
(d) Except to the extent that liability may not lawfully be excluded, We will not be under any liability to You ( or any of Your officers, agents or employees) for any direct or indirect loss or damage (including without limitation consequential loss or damage, loss of profit or anticipated profit, loss of data, loss of use, damage to goodwill and loss due to delay) however caused (including without limitation due to breach of contract, negligence and/or breach of statute) which may be suffered or incurred or which may arise from or in connection with Your use of this Website or Your use of or reliance upon any of the information, services and/or materials contained in it or provided by it to You or Our negligence or Our breach of Our obligations under these Terms and Conditions of Use.   
(e) The information contained in the Price Comparison Report is provided by Us in good faith, and We have taken all reasonable care in providing it. However, changes or events may occur which cause the information to be inaccurate or out of date. Accordingly, We do not warrant the accuracy or currency of that information and any reliance by You upon that information is at Your sole risk. 

6\. Links to other sites   
This Website may contain links to Websites maintained by other organisations. We have no affiliation with those Websites, do not endorse any material on those Websites and do not provide any warranty, or assume any responsibility, regarding the quality, accuracy, source, merchantability, fitness for purpose or any other aspect of the material on those Websites. 

7\. Copyright   
We own copyright in the contents of this Website. You may access and display these pages on a computer or a monitor, and print out for Your personal or internal business use any page or part of any page of this Website. All other use, copying or reproduction (including reproduction on any other Website) of any part of this Website is prohibited. 

8\. Viruses   
We do not represent or warrant that this Website and any other information or material contained in, downloaded or accessible from this Website, is free from computer viruses (including macro viruses) or any other defect or error which may affect Your software or systems. You should protect Your software and systems by installing and implementing Your own security checks and systems. 

9\. Cookies   
This Website uses a feature of Your Internet browser called a "cookie" to manage security and store report parameter information. If Your browser does not support cookies, or You have disabled this functionality, You may be unable to use this site. 

10\. Governing Law   
The law of Victoria governs these Terms and Conditions of Use, and You and We submit to the non-exclusive jurisdiction of the Courts of Victoria and the Federal Court of Australia.   
(e) Disclaimer 

The information contain in Holden's Websites is subject to change without notice, so please check back periodically. Holden's Websites are intended as general information only and is not complete or definitive. Holden is not liable and does not take any responsibility whatsoever for reliance on such information. 

Holden's sites may contain links to other Websites maintained by other organisations. Holden is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Websites.
